mathjobs.org 2019-06-11

# MATHJOBS.ORG PRIVACY STATEMENT

_**MATHJOBS.ORG PRIVACY STATEMENT**_

### Overall Statement

Security and privacy are our top priorities and we are doing our best to comply with relevant data protection regulations, to preserve your privacy and to make sure your data is available only to the intended parties. No others shall be granted access to your data unless required by law; and you will be notified by email as soon as possible if such access becomes necessary. Data is collected and used for the sole purpose of facilitating the application/hiring process. This site uses cookies for user session management. We don't use them for any other purposes. The data in the cookies is cleared once you have logged out. 

MathJobs is a service provided by the American Mathematical Society. The privacy statement of the American Mathematical Society applies to this site and supersedes this site's statement in case of any discrepancies. Please read the American Mathematical Society's [privacy statement](https://www.ams.org/about-us/privacy) for more details. 

### List of Data We Collect from Applicants and on behalf of Applicants

Category of Personal Data| Purposes of Processing  
---|---  
email address & selected password to our site | To secure your access to our site, and to communicate with you by us and the employers  
IP# and general location data of your recent accesses, and Google Analytics data | To help in diagnosing problems in user support, track website usage trends  
your full name, mailing address, work/home/cell phone# and skype name, employment institution and address | To provide them to the employers in your job applications. Other than your name, others are optional.  
Highest degree and date, thesis adviser, thesis title, degree institution | To provide them to the employers in your job applications. Other than your degree name, others are optional  
Primary research interest, secondary interest, tertiary interest, and a very brief synopsis of your current research interests, with research web page links | To provide them to the employers in your job applications. Other than your primary interest, others are optional  
Your answer to the question "Do you have U.S. citizenship or permanent residency?" | To provide them to the employers in your job applications, as required info by some employers. Employers in countries other than US might ask similar questions  
List of references to support your applications with their names, emails and affiliations | To provide them to the employers in your job application  
Files uploaded into your account for use in your job applications, such as cover letters, CVs, Research Statements, Teaching Statements, Publication Lists, Transcripts, and any other files as requested by the employers where you are applying | To provide them to the employers in your job applications  
Any data you have entered on the application forms for your current or recent applications, such as additional questions and EEO (gender, race, disability & veteran status, etc.) questions, as requested by each employer in their hiring process | To provide them to the employers in your job applications. Those data are not shared with any other employers  
The data you entered for the "Job Wanted" listing such as the description of the jobs you are looking for, and any selected files from your Portfolio to be viewable by employers | To make them viewable by all currently registered employers to select applicants from the public pool  
Reference letters uploaded by the reference writers and the employers (on the writer's behalf) | To provide them to the employers in your job applications. Reference letters are automatically deleted when the applicant account is deleted  
Institutional authorizations as requested on some job applications | To provide them to the employers in your job applications as part of your application package.  
|   
  
### Data Collection, Retention & Sharing

Data is collected and used for the sole purpose of facilitating the application/hiring process. The site only shares the application data with the employers where you have applied for positions, and we don't share them with any other employers or any other 3rd parties unless required by law. 

Applicants have the option on their coversheet form to remove their accounts and all files once all the jobs they've applied are finished, or they can remove their accounts right away if they don't have any current open applications. 

Applicant accounts including all related files in the Portfolio and reference letters will be automatically purged from the database 6 months (or 3 months if they have checked the 'off market' or 'remove my account' option on they coversheet form) after all jobs they have applied (if any) are finished, and they haven't logged in for 12 months. They can also contact us directly in case they need to remove their accounts quickly for some legitimate reason. 

Each employers can download all or any part of the application data submitted to their job openings to their local systems for any purposes they deem appropriate. Those downloaded data are no longer under our control, and they are governed by that employer's own policies. The application data will no longer be available or complete once the applicant accounts have been purged. The system keeps the snapshots online for 3 years. A historical copy of application listing (name, contact & degree info, application dates) and EEO data are available for 6 years before automatically removed. 

### Contact

Please contact us at mathjobs@ams.org for any questions or concerns. 

### Date of Last Update

5/25/2018.
